Wojciech Szymanski

Mobile: (0) 7487 633 866 Web: http://wszymanski.com **GitHub:** https://github.com/wojciech-szymanski Email: me@wszymanski.com

I am an experienced full stack developer with background in delivering large web applications both as a programmer and team lead as well. My portfolio includes intranets, online gambling websites, universities, back-office systems, e-commerce and large search driven portals. In my career I have been mostly involved in implementing functionality and UI of the web applications, as well as architecting solutions. At work, I mostly enjoy solving problems - thinking about best ways to join all different components of the website together and then putting those ideas into action.

Skills Summary

Technical: JavaScript, JSON, jQuery, HTML, CSS Team leadership Other:

> Angular, Node.JS, Express, MongoDB Solutions architecture

Karma, Protractor, Lodash

SCSS, Bootstrap

PHP5, MySQL, PostgreSQL

Elasticsearch Github, SVN, CVS Unix console

Gulp, Grunt, Bower

Functional specification writing

Wireframing (Axure) and UX Workshops facilitation and

stakeholder management

Working in Agile methodologies

Employment History

Apr 2016 – current JavaScript Developer at Mind Candy (contract)

Developing functionality of a new mobile game product using backend-as-a-service Game Sparks platform. Coding in vanilla JavaScript, HTML/Handlebars templates and MongoDB as a database.

Feb 2016 – Apr 2016 Web Developer at Quikkly (contract)

Quikkly provides tag generator and scanner for customised QR codes. I was hired to work on the UI of a dashboard that helps user create, manage and analyse their tags performance. Dashboard is built using Angular JS and job involves all aspects of frontend development, working with HTML / CSS and JS on a daily basis.

Product Developer at ANDigital Apr 2015 – Jan 2016

As a Product Developer, I took part in implementing digital solutions for ANDigital clients. I was involved in delivery phase, working together with client teams to help build and maintain various applications, from back office applications to client-facing websites. I also participated in developing internal tools useful for ANDigital business.

Achievements:

- Part of a larger team at Thomas Cook PLC which delivered new functionality on www.thomascook.com website for upcoming peak business period. Built back-office system for managing user account data by customer service teams using Node, Angular, MongoDB and Elasticsearch.
- · Built application used for internal training purposes using MEAN.io framework that provided a skeleton for development using Node, Angular and MongoDB.

Jan 2013 - Mar 2015 Web Technology Consultant at Squiz UK

As a Web Technology Consultant, I architected web solutions to solve business problems using predominantly Squiz Matrix CMS and Funnelback enterprise search engine software. During analysis phases for projects I was responsible for gathering clients' requirements, defining web solutions, producing annotated wireframes and detailed functional specification documents. During the build phases I lead and supported development teams and ensured that delivered end results adhered to previously scoped requirements and defined quality and web standards.

Achievements:

- Worked on various different projects and streams for one of the largest online gambling provider – William Hill Online <u>www.williamhill.com</u>. I successfully led and delivered migration of the mobile platforms onto Squiz Matrix CMS.
- Defined technical solution for a new version of bet placing application for William Hill. It was integrated with business logic API, built with Angular and tested using Protractor framework. I also helped re-engineer caching issues which were crucial for publishing promotional content. All projects involved communication across multiple teams and stakeholders, with often changing requirements and Agile / TDD methodology in place.
- Solution owner and technical lead of a successful new website redesign for University of Hertfordshire - www.herts.ac.uk Project involved complex migration of existing course database from bespoke CMS to the new platform and integration with Funnelback search engine. During build and delivery phases, I actively supported and led the development teams.
- Technical lead on numerous projects for government agencies or local councils.
 Defined solutions for integrating CMS with the APIs of Campaign Monitor tool.
 Specified process flow of electoral office finder, with combined use of geolocation,
 Postcode Anywhere and Funnelback search engine.

Apr 2010 – Sep 2012 Web Developer / Technical Lead at Squiz Australia

During my employment at Squiz Australia, I played a key role in delivering projects in collaboration with Squiz Poland. As a tech lead I was involved in projects throughout their life cycle starting with requirements gathering process and functional specification writing, and moving on to a technical lead role during the build phase, testing and delivery. Besides guiding teams of frontend developers, I also actively participated in the implementation and development phase myself by developing more complex modules.

Achievements:

- Participated in a website redesign for a tourism industry client www.sydney.com and queries that integrated Squiz Matrix CMS with external MSSQL database. I also developed interactive maps module using JavaScript, Open Layers library and integrating it fully with Funnelback search engine.
- Technical lead on three large intranet/website projects with Australian government departments – <u>www.dhs.vic.gov.au</u>. Successfully defined functional requirements and actively co-ordinated work between teams based in Poland and Australia. Challenges involved providing a single source of content and administration interface for both intranet and public facing websites.

Jul 2008 – Apr 2010 Web Developer at Squiz Poland

As a web developer in Squiz Poland, I played key role in product development cycle for Squiz Matrix CMS. My duties involved building new features, fixing reported software bugs and maintaining automated unit tests. During this time I also supported and took part in website builds for Squiz UK and PL clients, where my role was versatile and involved coding front-end interfaces and scripting content migration in PHP.

Achievements:

- Active part in product development, coding and unit testing new features integrated into Squiz Matrix CMS
- Took part in a large implementation of online betting website www.youwin.com. I
 was the lead developer of the front-end interface for placing bets, which integrated
 with the API of external application handling business logic. Technologies used –
 JavaScript / JSON / AJAX.

Jul 2007 – Feb 2008 Web Developer at Artamea Poland

Responsibilities:

• Development of an ERP system for a food distribution company. Bespoke system built using PHP / MySQL / JavaScript / AJAX.

Education

2003 – 2008 Technical University in Szczecin, Poland

MSc in Computer Science, specialised in mobile networks and technologies, thesis topic: Development of QoS mechanisms in 2G and 3G networks

Courses and Certifications

April 2015 Professional Scrum Master Lvl 1

Passed first level certification for Scrum Master issued by Scrum.org.

August 2014 M101P - MongoDB for Developers

Took part in a six-week course covering the basics of MongoDB, including brief Python introduction. Finished with the score of 95%.

References available on request